all righty guys welcome back and in this video I'm going to show you guys a
所有用右手球员欢迎回来，并在此 视频我 要 告诉 你们 一个人
really cool way to get the largest or smallest elements from a list or set and
真正酷的方式来获得 最大的或 列表或集合中的最小元素
if you guys are like oh my god this is like beginner stuff I'd know I'm just
如果你们真的喜欢我的 天啊 像初学者的东西， 我知道 我只是
going to have a list I'm going to sort it and then I'll get like the last three
有一个列表，我打算 排序 它， 然后我会 像过去三年
elements or the first three depending on how I sorted it but the question is what
元素或前三个取决于 我如何排序， 但问题是什么
happens if you have like a custom object like what happens if you has have a
如果你 喜欢 自定义对象就会发生 就像你有一个
employee class and they have ID numbers in names and I don't know like their
员工班，他们有身份证号码 在名字和我不 知道 他们的
profession and their salary and you need to sort them all by salary or ID number
职业和他们的工资，你需要 按工资或身份证号码对它们进行排序
how the heck do you do that well welcome to heap q so heap Q is essentially just
你是如何做到的那样 受欢迎 堆q所以堆 Q基本上 就是
a special type of EQ algorithm and it just allows you to sort stuff really easily I'm going to show you guys a cool
一种特殊类型的 EQ算法和它 只是让你真正排序的东西 很容易， 我会告诉 你们很酷
tricks but before let's just go ahead and use it to sort something really easy
技巧，但在让我们继续前进 并用它来分类非常简单的东西
so I'm going to pretend that I have a list of grades let me just pick the Mike
所以我要 假装我有一个 成绩列表让我选择迈克
of will say that we yet can upgrades more than 100 so I'll do like 130 266 99 and 5 whatever alright so I have a bunch
会 说 我们还可以升级 超过100所以我会喜欢130 266 99 5 一切好吗 所以我有一堆
of random numbers in there and say that I want to get like the three highest grade so maybe I'm a teacher and I'm
在那里 随机 数字，并 说 我想得到这样的三个最高 等级所以也许我是老师而且我是
going to take the three highest grades from every student and average them together whatever so what we can do is
要取三个最高分 来自每个学生并平均他们 无论如何，我们能做的就是
this we can use heap queue and we can just say n largest so this allows you to
这个我们可以使用堆 队列，我们​​可以 只说n最大所以这可以让你
get a certain number of largest items so if you only want the biggest one you can just type 1 if you want the 3 biggest
得到一定数量的最大项目 如果你只是想最大的一个，你可以 如果你想要 3个最大的， 只需 输入1
ones then just like 3 right there and the other parameter that it takes is
那些然后就像3在那里 和 它需要的另一个参数 是
just what is data said that you're trying to find so grades so what we're saying is looking grades and give me the
什么是数据说你是 试图找到如此成绩所以我们是什么 说是找分， 然后给我
3 largest values run and boom so it work orders it nicely for you so 654 532 and
3个最大的 价值运行和繁荣，所以它的工作 订购它很好，所以654 532和
132 alright pretty cool but you know we could probably have the
132 好吧很酷，但 你 知道我们 可能有
that earlier I mean we already know how like the sort list and we can just get
早些时候我的意思是我们已经 知道了 像排序列表，我们可以得到
like the first three elements ourselves so nothing special so the question
就像前三个元素一样 所以没有什么特别的问题
becomes why is this useful well let's say that we had a data set like this hold on hold on copying it alright so I
成为为什么这个有用的好吧 说我们有一个数据集，像 这样 暂时把它复制 好， 所以我
just copied that I had it so you know I didn't think you guys should watch me type all this so this is pretty much a
只是复制了我拥有它所以你知道我 不认为你们应该看着我 输入所有这些，所以这几乎 是一个
list of dictionaries now even though this is just a list of dictionaries you
尽管如此 ， 现在的词典列表 这只是 你 的 词典 列表
can actually use this method on your own custom class so if you had a class of
实际上可以自己使用这种方法 自定义类， 所以如果你有一个 类
like NHL players or your friends or anything so it's going to work the same
像NHL球员或你的朋友或 任何事情， 所以它会 一样的工作
I just wanted to give you guys a quick little data set for this tutorial so
我只是想快点给你们 为本 教程设置的数据很少
what we're going to do in this case is let's say that we wanted to give what am I going to try to find I don't know
在这种情况下我们要做的 是 让我们说我们想要 给出什么 我会试着找到我不知道的
maybe I was buying stocks and I wanted to find the two cheapest stocks so of course right now we can see
也许我是买股票而我想要的 找到最便宜的两个 股票当然，我们现在可以看到
that those are F and this is actually forward and this tuna is actually a
那些 是 F，这实际上是 向前，这个金枪鱼实际上是一个
company I made it up so Apple Google forward Microsoft and tuna but let's say
我把它改编成Apple Google 转发微软和金枪鱼，但 让我们说
that we had like a thousand and we wanted to find the cheapest ones so what
我们有一千个和我们一样 想 找到最便宜的人还等什么
we could do is this print keep queue just like before and anytime you want
我们能做的就是这个打印保持队列 就像之前和任何时候你想要的一样
the smallest let's say we want the two smallest you use n smallest and of
最小的 让我们说我们想要这 两个 最小的你使用n最小和
course the first one is how many values that we want just two and the second one
当然第一个是 多少价值观 我们 只 想要 两个和第二个
is of course what is the data set that you're trying to have me sift through
当然什么 是数据集， 你想让我筛选一下
well just these stocks right here but now check this out so these elements
这些股票就在这里，但是 现在检查一下这些元素
right here they don't just have one value like a list they have a ticker
就在这里，他们不仅仅有一个 像列表一样，他们 有一个自动收报机
they have a price maybe they have an ID number maybe I have like a datum for
他们有一个价格，也许他们有一个ID 数字也许我喜欢的数据
some reason whatever so this is only going to work with a simple data set
某种原因，所以这只是 打算 用一个简单的数据集工作
however if you want to sort by price then you can actually add the attribute
但是如果你想按价格排序 然后你 可以实际添加属性
is the last thing so we already know how lambdas work great I think I made it
是最后一件事，所以我们已经知道如何 lambdas很棒我觉得我做到了
sore about those so what we're going to do is we're going to say lambda make a
关于那些 我们要去的 东西 我们会说lambda会成为一个
really quick compact function and for each stock just give me the stock
非常快速紧凑的功能和 每只股票都给我股票
price now again you can put ticker in here you can put price you can put any
价格现在再次你可以把自动收报机 在这里你可以把价格放在任何地方
attribute for your object or whatever say you're trying to sift through and
您的对象或其他任何属性 说你正试图 筛选 和
check this out boom or roast it so it returns this is actually from before
检查这个繁荣或烤它所以它 返回这实际上是从 以前
right here but this returns Ford in tuna so how freaking awesome is that if you
就在这里，但这让 金枪鱼 回归 福特 所以， 如果你 ，那真是太棒了
guys ever try to sort your own custom classes or objects it was probably a
伙计们试图按自己的习惯排序 类或对象可能是一个
pain in the butt but boom roasted there you go so again whenever you're using a
屁股上的疼痛， 但在那里 热潮 你每次使用时都会这样
simple set you can use just two parameters whenever you're using your
简单的设置你可以只使用 两个 您使用时的参数
own custom objects or a more complex set like this whether it's JSON or your own
拥有自定义对象或更 复杂的 集合 像这样是JSON还是你自己的
custom one or your classes or whatever do this boom rose that thing guys for
自定义一个或你的类或 其他什么 做到这一点的繁荣 上涨 那件事家伙
watching I'll see you next
看着我接下来会见到你